<?xml version="1.0"?>
<nlmSearchResult>
  <term>"diabetes"</term>
  <file>viv_NOF8Ea</file>
  <server>pvlbsrch05</server>
  <count>191</count>
  <retstart>0</retstart>
  <retmax>10</retmax>
  <list num="191" start="0" per="10">
    <document rank="2" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/diabetes.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Sugar &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">DM</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; is a disease in which your blood glucose, or sugar, levels are too high.  Glucose comes from the foods you eat. Insulin is a hormone that helps the glucose get into your cells to give them energy.  With Type 1 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your body does not make insulin.  With Type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, the more common type, your body does not make or use insulin well. Without enough insulin, the glucose stays in your blood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over time, having too much glucose in your blood can cause serious problems.    It can damage your eyes, kidneys, and nerves. &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; can also cause heart disease, stroke and even the need to remove a limb. Pregnant women can also get &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, called gestational &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A blood test can show if you have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;.  Exercise, weight control and sticking to your meal plan can help control your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. You should also monitor your glucose level and take medicine if prescribed. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Digestive System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Seniors</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Metabolic Problems</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; is a disease in which your blood glucose, or sugar, levels are too high.  Glucose comes  ... cells to give them energy.  With Type 1 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your body does not make insulin.  With Type  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="0" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/diabetestype1.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; Type 1</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Insulin-Dependent &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Type I &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Juvenile &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Insulin-dependent &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; means your blood glucose, or blood sugar, is too 
high.  With Type 1 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your pancreas does not make insulin. Insulin is a hormone that 
helps glucose get into your cells to give them energy. Without insulin, too much glucose 
stays in your blood.  Over time, high blood glucose can lead to serious problems with your 
heart, eyes, kidneys, nerves, and gums and teeth. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type 1 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; happens most often in children and young adults but can appear at any 
age. Symptoms may include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Being very thirsty &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Urinating often &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Feeling very hungry or tired &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Losing weight without trying &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Having sores that heal slowly &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Having dry, itchy skin &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Losing the feeling in your feet or having tingling in your feet &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Having blurry eyesight &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A blood test can show if you have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. If you do, you will need to take insulin for 
the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;, Type 1</content>
      <content name="groupName">Digestive System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Children and Teenagers</content>
      <content name="groupName">Immune System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; means your blood glucose, or blood sugar, is too 
high.  With Type 1 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your pancreas does not make insulin. Insulin is  ... kidneys, nerves, and gums and teeth.  Type 1 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; happens most often in children and young adults  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="1" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/diabetestype2.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; Type 2</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Non-Insulin Dependent &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Type II &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Sugar &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; means your blood glucose, or blood sugar, is too high.  With Type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, the more common type, your body does not make or use insulin well. Insulin is a hormone that helps glucose get into your cells to give them energy. Without insulin, too much glucose stays in your blood.  Over time, high blood glucose can lead to serious problems with your heart, eyes, kidneys, nerves, gums and teeth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have a higher risk of type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; if you are older, obese, have a family history of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, or do not exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The symptoms of type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; appear slowly.  Some people do not notice symptoms at all.  The symptoms can include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being very thirsty&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Urinating often&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feeling very hungry or tired&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Losing weight without trying&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having sores that heal slowly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having blurry eyesight&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A blood test can show if you have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. Many people can manage their &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; through healthy eating, physical activity, and blood glucose testing.  Some people also need to take &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; medicines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;, Type 2</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; means your blood glucose, or blood sugar, is too high.  With Type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, the more common type, your body does not  ... You have a higher risk of type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; if you are older, obese, have a family  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="3" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/diabetesandpregnancy.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Pregnancy</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Pregnancy and &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Gestational &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; is a disease in which your blood glucose, or 
sugar, levels are too high. 
When you are pregnant, too much glucose is not good for your baby. Out of every 100 pregnant women in the United States, between three and eight get 
gestational &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. Gestational &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes is diabetes&lt;/span&gt; that happens for the first time when 
a woman is pregnant. Gestational &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; goes away when you have your baby, but it does 
increase your risk for having &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you already have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; before you get pregnant, you need to monitor and 
control your blood sugar levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Either type of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; during pregnancy raises the risk of problems for the baby and 
the mother. To help reduce these risks, you should follow your meal plan, exercise, test your blood sugar and take your medicine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Pregnancy in Diabetics</content>
      <content name="groupName">Pregnancy and Reproduction</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Female Reproductive System</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; is a disease in which your blood glucose, or 
sugar, levels are too high. 
When you  ... United States, between three and eight get 
gestational &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. Gestational &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes is diabetes&lt;/span&gt; that happens for the  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="4" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/diabetescomplications.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; Complications</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;If you have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your blood sugar levels are too high. Over time, this can cause problems with other body functions, such as your kidneys, nerves, feet, and eyes. Having &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; can also put you at a higher risk for heart disease and bone and joint disorders.  Other long-term complications of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; include skin problems, digestive problems, sexual dysfunction, and problems with your teeth and gums.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Very high or very low blood sugar levels can also lead to emergencies in people with &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. The cause can be an underlying infection, certain medicines, or even the medicines you take to control your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. If you feel nauseated, sluggish or shaky, seek emergency care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Diabetic Cardiomyopathies</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; Complications</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Metabolic Problems</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="snippet"> If you have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your blood sugar levels are too high. Over time, this can cause problems with other body functions, such as your kidneys, nerves, feet, and eyes. Having &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; can also put you at a higher risk  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="5" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/diabetesinsipidus.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; Insipidus</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">DI</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; insipidus (DI) causes frequent urination. You become extremely thirsty, so you drink. Then you urinate. This cycle can keep you from sleeping or even make you wet the bed. Your body produces big volumes of urine that are almost all water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DI is different from &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes mellitus&lt;/span&gt; (DM), which involves insulin problems and high blood sugar. The symptoms can be similar; however, DI is related to how your kidneys handle fluids. It's much less common than DM. Urine and blood tests can show which one you have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Usually, DI is caused by a problem with your pituitary gland or your kidneys.  
Treatment depends on the cause of the problem.  Medicines can often help.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; Insipidus</content>
      <content name="groupName">Kidneys and Urinary System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Metabolic Problems</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; insipidus (DI) causes frequent urination. You become extremely thirsty, so you drink. Then you urinate. This  ... are almost all water. DI is different from &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes mellitus&lt;/span&gt; (DM), which involves insulin problems and high  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="6" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/diabetesmedicines.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; Medicines</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Insulin</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hypoglycemic Medicines</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; means your blood glucose, or blood sugar, is too high. If you can't control your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; with wise food choices and physical activity, you may need &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; medicines. The kind of medicine you take depends on your type of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your schedule, and your other health conditions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Type 1 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your pancreas does not make insulin. Insulin is a hormone that helps glucose get into your cells to give them energy. Without insulin, too much glucose stays in your blood. If you have type 1 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, you will need to take insulin. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, the most common type, can start when the body doesn't use insulin as it should. If your body can't keep up with the need for insulin, you may need to take pills.  Some people need both insulin and pills. Along with meal planning and physical activity, &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; pills help people with type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; or gestational &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; keep their blood glucose levels on target. Several kinds of pills are available. Each works in a different way. Many people take two or three kinds of pills. Some people take combination pills. Combination pills contain two kinds of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; medicine in one tablet. Some people take pills and insulin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Hypoglycemic Agents</content>
      <content name="mesh">Insulin</content>
      <content name="mesh">Insulins</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Drug Therapy</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; means your blood glucose, or blood sugar, is too high. If you can't control your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; with wise food choices and physical activity, you may need &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; medicines. The kind of medicine you take depends  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="7" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/prediabetes.html">
      <content name="title">Pre-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Insulin Resistance</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Pre-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; means you have blood glucose levels that are higher than normal but not high enough to be called &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. Glucose comes from the foods you eat. Too much glucose in your blood can damage your body over time. If you have pre-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, you are more likely to develop type 2 &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, heart disease, and stroke.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people with pre-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; don't have any symptoms. Your doctor can test your blood to find out if your blood glucose levels are higher than normal. If you are 45 years old or older, your doctor may recommend that you be tested for pre-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, especially if you are overweight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Losing weight - at least 5 to 10 percent of your starting weight - can prevent or delay &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; or even reverse pre-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. That's 10 to 20 pounds for someone who weighs 200 pounds. You can lose weight by cutting down on the amount of calories and fat you eat and being physically active at least 30 minutes a day. Being physically active makes your body's insulin work better. Your doctor may also prescribe medicine to help control the amount of glucose in your blood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Prediabetic State</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Pre-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; means you have blood glucose levels that are higher than normal but not high enough to be called &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. Glucose comes from the foods you eat. Too  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="8" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/diabeticdiet.html">
      <content name="title">Diabetic Diet</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;If you have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your body cannot make or properly use insulin.  This leads to high blood glucose, or sugar, levels in your blood. Healthy eating helps keep your blood sugar in your target range.  It is a critical part of managing your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, because controlling your blood sugar can prevent the complications of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A registered dietitian can help make an eating plan just for you.  It should take into account your weight, medicines, lifestyle, and other health problems you have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Healthy diabetic eating includes
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Limiting foods that are high in sugar &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eating smaller portions, spread out over the day&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being careful about when and how many carbohydrates you eat&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eating a variety of whole-grain foods, fruits and vegetables every day&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eating less fat&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Limiting your use of alcohol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Using less salt&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Diabetic Diet</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Food and Nutrition</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="snippet"> If you have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, your body cannot make or properly use insulin.  This leads to high blood glucose, or sugar, levels in your  ... It is a critical part of managing your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, because controlling your blood sugar can prevent the  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="9" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/diabeticeyeproblems.html">
      <content name="title">Diabetic Eye Problems</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Diabetic Retinopathy</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Do you know what causes the most blindness in U.S. adults? It is an eye problem caused by &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, called diabetic retinopathy. Your retina is the light-sensitive tissue at the back of your eye. You need a healthy retina to see clearly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diabetic retinopathy happens when &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; damages the tiny blood vessels inside your retina. You may not notice at first. Symptoms can include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Blurry or double vision&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rings, flashing lights or blank spots&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dark or floating spots &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pain or pressure in one or both of your eyes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trouble seeing things out of the corners of your eyes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, you should have a complete eye exam every year. Finding and treating problems early may save your vision. Treatment often includes laser treatment or surgery. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes&lt;/span&gt; and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Diabetic Retinopathy</content>
      <content name="groupName">Eyes and Vision</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Diabetes Mellitus&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... adults? It is an eye problem caused by &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt;, called diabetic retinopathy. Your retina is the light- ... retina to see clearly. Diabetic retinopathy happens when &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;diabetes&lt;/span&gt; damages the tiny blood vessels inside your retina.  ... </content>
    </document>
  </list>
</nlmSearchResult>
