<?xml version="1.0"?>
<nlmSearchResult>
  <term>"hyperkalemia"</term>
  <file>viv_ux3eXz</file>
  <server>pvlbsrch05</server>
  <count>4</count>
  <retstart>0</retstart>
  <retmax>10</retmax>
  <list num="4" start="0" per="10">
    <document rank="0" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/fluidandelectrolytebalance.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Fluid and Electrolyte Balance&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Electrolytes</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Dehydration</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hyponatremia</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hypokalemia</content>
      <content name="altTitle">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Hyperkalemia&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hypercalcemia</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hypocalcemia</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Electrolytes are minerals in your body that have an electric charge. They are in your blood, urine and body fluids. Maintaining the right balance of electrolytes helps your body's blood chemistry, muscle action and other processes. Sodium, calcium, potassium, chlorine, phosphate and magnesium are all electrolytes. You get them from the foods you eat and the fluids you drink.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Levels of electrolytes in your body can become too low or too high. That can happen when the amount of water in your body changes. Causes include some medicines, vomiting, diarrhea, sweating or kidney problems. Problems most often occur with levels of sodium, potassium or calcium. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Water-Electrolyte Imbalance</content>
      <content name="mesh">Water-Electrolyte Balance</content>
      <content name="groupName">Food and Nutrition</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Electrolytes are minerals in your body that have an electric charge. They are in your blood, urine and body fluids. Maintaining the right balance of electrolytes  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="1" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/potassium.html">
      <content name="title">Potassium</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hypokalemia</content>
      <content name="altTitle">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Hyperkalemia&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Potassium is a mineral that the body needs to work normally. It helps nerves and muscles communicate. It also helps move nutrients into cells and waste products out of cells. A diet rich in potassium helps to offset some of sodium's harmful effects on blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people get all the potassium they need from what they eat and drink. Sources of potassium in the diet include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Leafy greens, such as spinach and collards&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fruit from vines, such as grapes and blackberries&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Root vegetables, such as carrots and potatoes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Citrus fruits, such as oranges and grapefruit&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Potassium</content>
      <content name="mesh">Potassium, Dietary</content>
      <content name="groupName">Food and Nutrition</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Potassium is a mineral that the body needs to work normally. It helps nerves and muscles communicate. It also helps move nutrients into cells and waste products  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="2" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/endocrinediseases.html">
      <content name="title">Endocrine Diseases</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Multiple Endocrine Neoplasia</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Your endocrine system includes eight major glands throughout your body. These glands make hormones. Hormones are chemical messengers.  They travel through your bloodstream to tissues or organs. Hormones work slowly and affect body processes from head to toe. These include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Growth and development&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Metabolism - digestion, elimination, breathing, blood circulation and maintaining body temperature &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sexual function&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reproduction&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mood&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your hormone levels are too high or too low, you may have a hormone disorder. Hormone diseases also occur if your body does not respond to hormones the way it is supposed to.  Stress, infection and changes in your blood's &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;fluid and electrolyte balance&lt;/span&gt; can also influence hormone levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the United States, the most common endocrine disease is diabetes. There are many others. They are usually treated by controlling how much hormone your body makes. Hormone supplements can help if the problem is too little of a hormone.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Endocrine System Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... to.  Stress, infection and changes in your blood's &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;fluid and electrolyte balance&lt;/span&gt; can also influence hormone levels. In the United  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="3" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/kidneydiseases.html">
      <content name="title">Kidney Diseases</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Nephritis</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Polycystic Kidney Disease</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Renal Disease</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Your kidneys are two bean-shaped organs, each about the size of your fists. They are located near the middle of your back, just below the rib cage. Inside each kidney about a million tiny structures called nephrons filter blood. They remove waste products and extra water, which become urine. The urine flows through tubes called ureters to your bladder, which stores the urine until you go to the bathroom. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most kidney diseases attack the nephrons.  This damage may leave kidneys unable to remove wastes. Causes can include genetic problems, injuries, or medicines.  You are at greater risk for kidney disease if you have diabetes, high blood pressure, or a close family member with kidney disease. Chronic kidney disease damages the nephrons slowly over several years. Other kidney problems include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cancer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cysts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stones&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Infections&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your doctor can run tests to find out if you have kidney disease.  If your kidneys fail completely, a kidney transplant or dialysis can replace the work your kidneys normally do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Kidney Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Kidneys and Urinary System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Your kidneys are two bean-shaped organs, each about the size of your fists. They are located near the middle of your back, just below the rib cage. Inside  ... </content>
    </document>
  </list>
</nlmSearchResult>
