<?xml version="1.0"?>
<nlmSearchResult>
  <term>"inflammation"</term>
  <file>viv_vLjiOl</file>
  <server>pvlbsrch05</server>
  <count>73</count>
  <retstart>0</retstart>
  <retmax>10</retmax>
  <list num="73" start="0" per="10">
    <document rank="0" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/giantcellarteritis.html">
      <content name="title">Giant Cell Arteritis</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Temporal Arteritis</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Giant cell arteritis is a disorder that causes &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of arteries of the scalp, neck, and arms. The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; narrows the arteries, which keeps blood from flowing well. Giant cell arteritis often occurs with another disorder called polymyalgia rheumatica. Both disorders are more common in women than in men. They almost always affect people over the age of 50.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early symptoms of giant cell arteritis resemble the flu:  fatigue, loss of appetite, and fever. Other symptoms include headaches, pain and tenderness over the temples, double vision or visual loss, dizziness, and problems with coordination and balance. You may also have pain in your jaw and tongue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your doctor will make the diagnosis based on your medical history, symptoms, and physical examination. There is no single test to diagnose giant cell arteritis, but you may have tests that measure &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Treatment is usually with corticosteroids. Early treatment is important; otherwise there is a risk of permanent vision loss or stroke.  However, when properly treated, giant cell arteritis rarely comes back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Giant Cell Arteritis</content>
      <content name="groupName">Blood, Heart and Circulation</content>
      <content name="groupName">Immune System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Giant cell arteritis is a disorder that causes &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of arteries of the scalp, neck, and arms. The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; narrows the arteries, which keeps blood from flowing  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="1" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/penisdisorders.html">
      <content name="title">Penis Disorders</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Penile Disorders</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Male Genital Disorders</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Peyronie's Disease</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Balanitis</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Problems with the penis can cause pain and affect a man's sexual function and fertility. 
Penis disorders include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Erectile dysfunction - inability to get or keep an 
erection &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Priapism - a painful erection that does not go away &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Peyronie's disease - bending of the penis during an erection due to a hard lump 
called a plaque &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Balanitis - &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the skin covering the head of the penis, most often in 
men and boys who have not been circumcised &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Penile cancer - a rare form of cancer, highly curable when caught early &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Penile Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Men</content>
      <content name="groupName">Sexual Health Issues</content>
      <content name="groupName">Male Reproductive System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... to a hard lump 
called a plaque   	Balanitis - &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the skin covering the head of the  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="2" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/peritonealdisorders.html">
      <content name="title">Peritoneal Disorders</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Peritonitis</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Your peritoneum is the tissue that lines your abdominal wall and covers most of the organs in your abdomen. A liquid, peritoneal fluid, lubricates the surface of this tissue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disorders of the peritoneum are not common. They include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Peritonitis - an &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the peritoneum&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cancer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complications from peritoneal dialysis&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Treatment of peritoneal disorders depends on the cause.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Peritoneal Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Digestive System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... peritoneum are not common. They include Peritonitis - an &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the peritoneum  Cancer  Complications from peritoneal  dialysis    ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="3" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/vasculitis.html">
      <content name="title">Vasculitis</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Angiitis</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Vasculitis is an &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the blood vessels. It happens when the body's immune system attacks the blood vessel by mistake. The cause is often unknown. Vasculitis can affect arteries, veins and capillaries. Arteries are vessels that carry blood from the heart to the body's organs. Veins are the vessels that carry blood back to the heart. Capillaries are tiny blood vessels that connect the small arteries and veins. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a blood vessel becomes inflamed, it can&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Narrow, making it more difficult for blood to get through &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Close off completely so that blood can't get through &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Stretch and weaken so much that it bulges and may burst and cause dangerous bleeding inside the body&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Symptoms of vasculitis can vary, but usually include fever, swelling and a general sense of feeling ill. The main goal of treatment is to stop the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt;. Steroids and other medicines to stop &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; are often helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Vasculitis</content>
      <content name="groupName">Blood, Heart and Circulation</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Vasculitis is an &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the blood vessels. It happens when the body's immune system attacks the blood vessel by mistake. The cause  ... main goal of treatment is to stop the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt;. Steroids and other medicines to stop &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; are  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="4" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/behcetssyndrome.html">
      <content name="title">Behcet's Syndrome</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Behcet's disease</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Behcet's syndrome is a disease that involves &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the blood vessels. It causes problems in many parts of the body. The most common symptoms are&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Sores in the mouth&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Sores on the sex organs &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Other skin sores &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Swelling of parts of the eye&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Pain, swelling and stiffness of the joints &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;More serious problems can include meningitis, blood clots, &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the digestive system and blindness. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doctors aren't sure what causes Behcet's. It is rare in the United States, but is common in the Middle East and Asia. It mainly affects people in their 20s and 30s. Diagnosing Behcet's can take a long time, because symptoms may come and go, and it may take months or even years to have all of the symptoms. There is no cure.  Treatment focuses on reducing pain and preventing serious problems. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Behcet Syndrome</content>
      <content name="groupName">Blood, Heart and Circulation</content>
      <content name="groupName">Eyes and Vision</content>
      <content name="groupName">Mouth and Teeth</content>
      <content name="groupName">Skin, Hair and Nails</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Behcet's syndrome is a disease that involves &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the blood vessels. It causes problems in many parts of the body. The most common symptoms are 	Sores in the mouth  	Sores  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="5" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/bronchialdisorders.html">
      <content name="title">Bronchial Disorders</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Bronchiolitis</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Bronchiectasis</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;The bronchi are two tubes that branch off the trachea, or windpipe. The bronchi carry air to your lungs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most common problem with the bronchi is bronchitis, an &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the tubes. Bronchitis can be acute or chronic. Other problems include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bronchiectasis, a condition in which damage to the airways causes them to widen and become flabby and scarred&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exercise-induced bronchospasm, which happens when the airways shrink while you are exercising&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bronchiolitis, an &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the small airways that branch off from the bronchi&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bronchopulmonary dysplasia, a condition affecting infants&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Treatment of bronchial disorders depends on the cause.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Bronchial Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Lungs and Breathing</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... common problem with the bronchi is bronchitis, an &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the tubes. Bronchitis can be acute or  ... airways shrink while you are exercising  Bronchiolitis, an &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the small airways that branch off from  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="6" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/bursitis.html">
      <content name="title">Bursitis</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;A bursa is a filmy-colored sac that protects and cushions your joints. Bursitis means &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of one of your bursa sacs. The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; may result from arthritis in the joint or injury or infection of a bursa. Bursitis produces pain and tenderness and may limit the movement of nearby joints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can get bursitis in your shoulders, elbows, hips, knees, heels and big toe. Injuries, overuse and repetitive stress are common causes of bursitis. Certain diseases, such as arthritis and gout, might also cause it. It sometimes occurs with tendinitis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can usually treat bursitis with rest, ice, and medicines to ease pain and reduce swelling. Other treatments include ultrasound, physical therapy, steroid injections and, in rare cases, surgery. Stretching before you exercise, strengthening your muscles and resting when you do repetitive tasks might help prevent bursitis. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Bursitis</content>
      <content name="groupName">Bones, Joints and Muscles</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... that protects and cushions your joints. Bursitis means &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of one of your bursa sacs. The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; may result from arthritis in the joint or  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="7" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/eyediseases.html">
      <content name="title">Eye Diseases</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Ophthalmology</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Pinguecula</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Some eye problems are minor and fleeting. But some lead to a permanent loss of vision. Common eye problems include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cataracts - clouded lenses&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Glaucoma - damage to the optic nerve from too much 
pressure in the eye&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Retinal disorders - problems with the nerve layer at 
the back of the eye&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Conjunctivitis - an  infection also known as pinkeye&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your best defense is to have regular checkups, because eye diseases do not always have 
symptoms. Early detection and treatment could prevent vision loss. See an eye care 
professional right away if you have a sudden change in vision or everything looks dim or if 
you see flashes of light. Other symptoms that need quick attention are pain, double vision, 
fluid coming from the eye and &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Eye Institute &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Eye Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Eyes and Vision</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... double vision, 
fluid coming from the eye and &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt;. NIH: National Eye Institute </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="8" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/hayfever.html">
      <content name="title">Hay Fever</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Pollen Allergy</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Each spring, summer, and fall, trees, weeds and grasses release tiny pollen grains into the air. Some of the pollen ends up in your nose and throat. This can trigger a type of allergy called hay fever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Symptoms can include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sneezing, often with a runny or clogged nose&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coughing and postnasal drip&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Itching eyes, nose and throat&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dark circles under the eyes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking medicines, using nasal sprays and rinsing out your nose can relieve symptoms. Allergy shots can help make you less sensitive to pollen and provide long-term relief.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Rhinitis, Allergic, Seasonal</content>
      <content name="groupName">Ear, Nose and Throat</content>
      <content name="groupName">Immune System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Each spring, summer, and fall, trees, weeds and grasses release tiny pollen grains into the air. Some of the pollen ends up in your nose and throat. This  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="9" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/wegenersgranulomatosis.html">
      <content name="title">Wegener's Granulomatosis</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Wegener's granulomatosis is a rare disease. It is a type of vasculitis, or &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the blood vessels. This limits the flow of blood to important organs, causing damage. It can affect any organ, but it mainly affects the sinuses, nose, trachea (windpipe), lungs and kidneys. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cause of Wegener's granulomatosis is unknown.  Symptoms may include joint pain, weakness, tiredness and cold symptoms such as a runny nose that doesn't get better. Doctors use blood tests and chest x-rays to diagnose the disease and rule out other causes of the symptoms. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early treatment is important. Most people improve with medicines to slow or stop the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Wegener Granulomatosis</content>
      <content name="groupName">Blood, Heart and Circulation</content>
      <content name="groupName">Kidneys and Urinary System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Lungs and Breathing</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... disease. It is a type of vasculitis, or &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt; of the blood vessels. This limits the flow  ... improve with medicines to slow or stop the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;inflammation&lt;/span&gt;.  NIH: National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases</content>
    </document>
  </list>
</nlmSearchResult>
