<?xml version="1.0"?>
<nlmSearchResult>
  <term>"metabolic</term>
  <file>viv_sm4QFA</file>
  <server>pvlbsrch05</server>
  <count>42</count>
  <retstart>0</retstart>
  <retmax>10</retmax>
  <list num="42" start="0" per="10">
    <document rank="0" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/metabolicsyndrome.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; Syndrome</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Insulin Resistance</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Syndrome X (&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt;)</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Insulin resistance syndrome</content>
      <content name="altTitle">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; Syndrome X</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; syndrome is a group of conditions that put you at risk for 
heart disease and diabetes. These 
conditions are  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;High blood pressure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	High blood sugar levels&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	High levels of 
triglycerides, a type of fat, in your blood &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Low levels of HDL, the good 
cholesterol, in your blood&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Too much fat around your waist&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all doctors agree on the definition or cause of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;metabolic&lt;/span&gt; syndrome. The cause might 
be insulin resistance. Insulin is a hormone your body produces to help you turn sugar from 
food into energy for your body. If you are insulin resistant, too much sugar builds up in 
your blood, setting the stage for disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; Syndrome X</content>
      <content name="groupName">Blood, Heart and Circulation</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; Problems</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; syndrome is a group of conditions that put you at risk for 
heart disease and diabetes.  ... doctors agree on the definition or cause of &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;metabolic&lt;/span&gt; syndrome. The cause might 
be insulin resistance. Insulin  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="1" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/metabolicdisorders.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; Disorders</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Mucolipidoses</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Mucopolysaccharidoses</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Metabolism is the process your body uses to get or make energy from the food you eat. Food is made up of proteins, carbohydrates and fats. Chemicals in your digestive system break the food parts down into sugars and acids, your body's fuel. Your body can use this fuel right away, or it can store the energy in your body tissues, such as your liver, muscles and body fat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;metabolic&lt;/span&gt; disorder occurs when abnormal chemical reactions in your body disrupt this process. When this happens, you might have too much of some substances or too little of other ones that you need to stay healthy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can develop a &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;metabolic&lt;/span&gt; disorder when some organs, such as your liver or pancreas, become diseased or do not function normally. Diabetes is an example. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Genetics/Birth Defects</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; Problems</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... as your liver, muscles and body fat. A &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;metabolic&lt;/span&gt; disorder occurs when abnormal chemical reactions in your  ... need to stay healthy.  You can develop a &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;metabolic&lt;/span&gt; disorder when some organs, such as your liver  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="2" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/laboratorytests.html">
      <content name="title">Laboratory Tests</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Blood Tests</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;If you've ever had to give a tube of blood or a little cup of urine in your doctor's office, you've had a laboratory test. Laboratory tests check a sample of your blood, urine or body tissues. A technician or your doctor analyzes the test samples to see if your results fall within the normal range. The tests use a range because what is normal differs from person to person. Many factors affect test results. These include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Your sex, age and race&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	What you eat and drink&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Medicines you take&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	How well you followed pre-test instructions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your doctor may also compare your results to results from previous tests. Laboratory tests are often part of a routine checkup to look for changes in your health. They also help doctors diagnose medical conditions, plan or evaluate treatments, and monitor diseases. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Clinical Laboratory Techniques</content>
      <content name="groupName">Diagnostic Tests</content>
      <content name="snippet"> If you've ever had to give a tube of blood or a little cup of urine in your doctor's office, you've had a laboratory test. Laboratory tests check a sample  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="3" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/geneticbraindisorders.html">
      <content name="title">Genetic Brain Disorders</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Brain Disorders, Inborn Genetic</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Maple Syrup Urine Disease</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Niemann-Pick Disease</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Inborn genetic brain disorders</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;A genetic disorder is a disease caused by a different form of a gene, called a variation, or a change in a gene, called a mutation. Genetic brain disorders specifically affect the development and function of the brain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some genetic brain disorders are due to random gene mutations or mutations caused by environmental exposure, such as cigarette smoke. Other disorders are inherited, which means that a mutated gene or group of genes is passed down through a family. Still other disorders are due to a combination of genetic changes and other outside factors. Some examples of genetic brain disorders include leukodystrophies, phenylketonuria, Tay-Sachs disease, and Wilson disease. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many people with genetic brain disorders fail to produce enough of certain proteins that influence brain development and function. These brain disorders can cause serious problems that affect the nervous system. Some are life-threatening.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Brain Diseases, &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt;, Inborn</content>
      <content name="groupName">Brain and Nerves</content>
      <content name="groupName">Genetics/Birth Defects</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Metabolic&lt;/span&gt; Problems</content>
      <content name="snippet"> A genetic disorder is a disease caused by a different form of a gene, called a variation, or a change in a gene, called a mutation. Genetic brain disorders  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="4" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/chronickidneydisease.html">
      <content name="title">Chronic Kidney Disease</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">CKD</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;You have two kidneys, each about the size of your fist.  Their main job is to filter wastes and excess water out of your blood to make urine. They also keep the body's chemical balance, help control blood pressure, and make hormones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chronic kidney disease (CKD) means that your kidneys are damaged and can't filter blood as they should. This damage can cause wastes to build up in your body. It can also cause other problems that can harm your health. Diabetes and high blood pressure are the most common causes of CKD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Treatment may include medicines to lower blood pressure, control blood glucose, and lower blood cholesterol. CKD can get worse over time. CKD may lead to kidney failure. The only treatment options for kidney failure are dialysis or a kidney transplantation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can take steps to keep your kidneys healthier longer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choose foods with less salt (sodium)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep your blood pressure below 130/80&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep your blood glucose in the target range, if you have diabetes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</content>
      <content name="groupName">Kidneys and Urinary System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> You have two kidneys, each about the size of your fist.  Their main job is to filter wastes and excess water out of your blood to make urine. They also keep  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="5" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/dementia.html">
      <content name="title">Dementia</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Senility</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Dementia is a word for a group of symptoms caused by disorders that affect the brain. It is not a specific disease. People with dementia may not be able to think well enough to do normal activities, such as getting dressed or eating. They may lose their ability to solve problems or control their emotions. Their personalities may change. They may become agitated or see things that are not there. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Memory loss is a common symptom of dementia. However, memory loss by itself does not mean you have dementia. People with dementia have serious problems with two or more brain functions, such as memory and language. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Many different diseases can cause dementia, including Alzheimer's disease and stroke. Drugs are available to treat some of these diseases. While these drugs cannot cure dementia or repair brain damage, they may improve symptoms or slow down the disease.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Dementia</content>
      <content name="groupName">Mental Health and Behavior</content>
      <content name="groupName">Seniors</content>
      <content name="groupName">Brain and Nerves</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Dementia is a word for a group of symptoms caused by disorders that affect the brain. It is not a specific disease. People with dementia may not be able to think  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="6" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/endocrinediseases.html">
      <content name="title">Endocrine Diseases</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Multiple Endocrine Neoplasia</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Your endocrine system includes eight major glands throughout your body. These glands make hormones. Hormones are chemical messengers.  They travel through your bloodstream to tissues or organs. Hormones work slowly and affect body processes from head to toe. These include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Growth and development&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Metabolism - digestion, elimination, breathing, blood circulation and maintaining body temperature &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sexual function&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reproduction&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mood&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your hormone levels are too high or too low, you may have a hormone disorder. Hormone diseases also occur if your body does not respond to hormones the way it is supposed to.  Stress, infection and changes in your blood's fluid and electrolyte balance can also influence hormone levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the United States, the most common endocrine disease is diabetes. There are many others. They are usually treated by controlling how much hormone your body makes. Hormone supplements can help if the problem is too little of a hormone.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Endocrine System Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Endocrine System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Your endocrine system includes eight major glands throughout your body. These glands make hormones. Hormones are chemical messengers.  They travel through  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="7" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/fluidandelectrolytebalance.html">
      <content name="title">Fluid and Electrolyte Balance</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Electrolytes</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Dehydration</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hyponatremia</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hypokalemia</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hyperkalemia</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hypercalcemia</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hypocalcemia</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Electrolytes are minerals in your body that have an electric charge. They are in your blood, urine and body fluids. Maintaining the right balance of electrolytes helps your body's blood chemistry, muscle action and other processes. Sodium, calcium, potassium, chlorine, phosphate and magnesium are all electrolytes. You get them from the foods you eat and the fluids you drink.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Levels of electrolytes in your body can become too low or too high. That can happen when the amount of water in your body changes. Causes include some medicines, vomiting, diarrhea, sweating or kidney problems. Problems most often occur with levels of sodium, potassium or calcium. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Water-Electrolyte Imbalance</content>
      <content name="mesh">Water-Electrolyte Balance</content>
      <content name="groupName">Food and Nutrition</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Electrolytes are minerals in your body that have an electric charge. They are in your blood, urine and body fluids. Maintaining the right balance of electrolytes  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="8" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/kidneydiseases.html">
      <content name="title">Kidney Diseases</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Nephritis</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Polycystic Kidney Disease</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Renal Disease</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Your kidneys are two bean-shaped organs, each about the size of your fists. They are located near the middle of your back, just below the rib cage. Inside each kidney about a million tiny structures called nephrons filter blood. They remove waste products and extra water, which become urine. The urine flows through tubes called ureters to your bladder, which stores the urine until you go to the bathroom. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most kidney diseases attack the nephrons.  This damage may leave kidneys unable to remove wastes. Causes can include genetic problems, injuries, or medicines.  You are at greater risk for kidney disease if you have diabetes, high blood pressure, or a close family member with kidney disease. Chronic kidney disease damages the nephrons slowly over several years. Other kidney problems include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cancer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cysts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stones&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Infections&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your doctor can run tests to find out if you have kidney disease.  If your kidneys fail completely, a kidney transplant or dialysis can replace the work your kidneys normally do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Kidney Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Kidneys and Urinary System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Your kidneys are two bean-shaped organs, each about the size of your fists. They are located near the middle of your back, just below the rib cage. Inside  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="9" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/muscledisorders.html">
      <content name="title">Muscle Disorders</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Myopathies</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Rhabdomyolysis</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Myopathy</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;
Your muscles help you move and help your body work. Different types of muscles have different jobs. There are many problems that can affect muscles. Muscle disorders can cause weakness, pain or even paralysis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There may be no known cause for a muscle disorder. Some known causes include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Injury or overuse, such as sprains or strains, cramps or tendinitis &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Genetics, such as muscular dystrophy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Some cancers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Inflammation, such as myositis&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Diseases of nerves that affect muscles&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Infections&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Certain medicines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Muscular Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Bones, Joints and Muscles</content>
      <content name="snippet"> 
Your muscles help you move and help your body work. Different types of muscles have different jobs. There are many problems that can affect muscles. Muscle  ... </content>
    </document>
  </list>
</nlmSearchResult>
