<?xml version="1.0"?>
<nlmSearchResult>
  <term>"obesity"</term>
  <file>viv_LdXPlb</file>
  <server>pvlbsrch05</server>
  <count>37</count>
  <retstart>0</retstart>
  <retmax>10</retmax>
  <list num="37" start="0" per="10">
    <document rank="1" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/obesity.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Overweight&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt; means having too much body &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;fat&lt;/span&gt;. It is different from being &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;, which 
means weighing too much.  The weight may come from muscle, bone, &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;fat&lt;/span&gt; and/or body water.  
Both terms mean that a person's weight is greater than what's considered healthy for his or 
her height. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt; occurs over time when you eat more calories than you use. The balance between 
calories-in and calories-out differs for each person. Factors that might tip the balance 
include your genetic makeup, overeating, eating high-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;fat&lt;/span&gt; foods and not being physically 
active. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being obese increases your risk of diabetes, heart disease, stroke, arthritis and some 
cancers. If you are obese, losing even 5 to 10 percent of your weight can delay or prevent 
some of these diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Food and Nutrition</content>
      <content name="groupName">Metabolic Problems</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt; means having too much body &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;fat&lt;/span&gt;. It is different from being &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;, which 
means weighing too  ... what's considered healthy for his or 
her height.  &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt; occurs over time when you eat more calories  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="0" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/obesityinchildren.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt; in Children</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Childhood &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt; means having too much body &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;fat&lt;/span&gt;. It is different from 
being &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;, which means weighing too much. Both terms mean that a person's weight is 
greater than what is considered healthy for his or her height.  Children grow at different 
rates, so it isn't always easy to know when a child is obese or &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;. Ask your doctor 
to measure your child's height and weight to determine if he or she is in a healthy 
range.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a weight loss program is necessary, involve the whole family in healthy habits so 
your child doesn't feel singled out. You can encourage healthy eating by serving more 
fruits and vegetables and buying fewer sodas and high-calorie, high-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;fat&lt;/span&gt; snack foods.  
Physical activity can also help your child overcome &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;obesity&lt;/span&gt; or being &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;. Kids need 
about 60 minutes each day. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Children and Teenagers</content>
      <content name="groupName">Food and Nutrition</content>
      <content name="groupName">Metabolic Problems</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt; means having too much body &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;fat&lt;/span&gt;. It is different from 
being &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;, which means weighing too  ... Physical activity can also help your child overcome &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;obesity&lt;/span&gt; or being &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;. Kids need 
about 60 minutes  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="2" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/weightlosssurgery.html">
      <content name="title">Weight Loss Surgery</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Bariatric Surgery</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Gastric Bypass</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Gastroplasty</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Stomach Stapling</content>
      <content name="altTitle">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt; Surgery</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Gastric banding</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;If you're very &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt; and can't lose pounds with a healthy diet and exercise, surgery might be an option for you. The surgery is usually for men who are at least 100 pounds &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt; and women who are at least 80 pounds &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;. If you are somewhat less &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;, surgery still might be an option if you also have diabetes, heart disease or sleep apnea. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weight loss surgery limits the amount of food you can take in. Some operations also restrict the amount of food you can digest.  Many people who have the surgery lose weight quickly. If you follow diet and exercise recommendations, you can keep most of the weight off. The surgery has risks and complications, however, including infections, hernias and blood clots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt;, Morbid</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Obesity&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Bariatric Surgery</content>
      <content name="groupName">Digestive System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Surgery and Rehabilitation</content>
      <content name="groupName">Metabolic Problems</content>
      <content name="snippet"> If you're very &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt; and can't lose pounds with a healthy diet and exercise, surgery might be an option for you. The surgery is usually for men who  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="3" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/bodyweight.html">
      <content name="title">Body Weight</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Overweight&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Underweight</content>
      <content name="altTitle">BMI</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt; Do you know whether or not your current weight is healthy?  "Underweight", "normal", &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;"overweight"&lt;/span&gt;, and "obese" are all labels for ranges of weight. Obese and &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt; mean that your weight is greater than it should be for your health. Underweight means that it is lower than it should be for your health. Your healthy body weight depends on your gender and height.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A sudden, unexpected change in weight can be a sign of a medical problem.  Causes for sudden weight loss can include thyroid problems, cancer, infectious diseases, digestive diseases, and certain medicines. Sudden weight gain can be due to medications, thyroid problems, heart failure, and kidney disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good nutrition and exercise can help in losing weight Eating extra calories within a well-balanced diet and treating any underlying medical problems can help to add weight.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Body Weight Changes</content>
      <content name="mesh">Body Weight</content>
      <content name="groupName">Food and Nutrition</content>
      <content name="groupName">Metabolic Problems</content>
      <content name="snippet">  Do you know whether or not your current weight is healthy?  "Underweight", "normal", &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;"overweight"&lt;/span&gt;, and "obese" are all labels for ranges of weight. Obese and  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="4" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/cancer.html">
      <content name="title">Cancer</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Malignancy</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Carcinoma</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Neoplasms</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Tumor</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Oncology</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Cancer begins in your cells, which are the building blocks of your body.   Normally, your body forms new cells as you need them, replacing old cells that die. Sometimes this process goes wrong. New cells grow even when you don't need them, and old cells don't die when they should. These extra cells can form a mass called a tumor. Tumors can be benign or malignant. Benign tumors aren't cancer while malignant ones are. Cells from malignant tumors can invade nearby tissues. They can also break away and spread to other parts of the body. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most cancers are named for where they start. For example, lung cancer starts in the lung, and breast cancer starts in the breast. The spread of cancer from one part of the body to another is called metastasis. Symptoms and treatment depend on the cancer type and how advanced it is. Treatment plans may include surgery, radiation and/or chemotherapy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Cancer Institute&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Neoplasms</content>
      <content name="groupName">Cancers</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Cancer begins in your cells, which are the building blocks of your body.   Normally, your body forms new cells as you need them, replacing old cells that die.  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="5" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/sleepapnea.html">
      <content name="title">Sleep Apnea</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Apnea, Sleep</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Sleep-disordered breathing</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Sleep apnea is a common disorder that can be serious. In sleep apnea, your breathing stops or gets very shallow. Each pause in breathing typically lasts 10 to 20 seconds or more. These pauses can occur 20 to 30 times or more an hour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most common type is obstructive sleep apnea. That means you are unable to get enough air through your mouth and nose into your lungs. When that happens, the amount of oxygen in your blood may drop. Normal breaths resume with a snort or choking sound. People with sleep apnea often snore loudly. However, not everyone who snores has sleep apnea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When your sleep is interrupted throughout the night, you can be drowsy during the day. People with sleep apnea are at higher risk for car crashes, work-related accidents and other medical problems. If you have it, it is important to get treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Sleep Apnea Syndromes</content>
      <content name="groupName">Brain and Nerves</content>
      <content name="groupName">Lungs and Breathing</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Sleep apnea is a common disorder that can be serious. In sleep apnea, your breathing stops or gets very shallow. Each pause in breathing typically lasts 10  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="6" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/weightcontrol.html">
      <content name="title">Weight Control</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Dieting</content>
      <content name="altTitle">BMI</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;If you are &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;, you are not alone.  Sixty-six percent of adults in the U.S. are &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt; or obese.   Achieving a healthy weight can help you control your cholesterol, blood pressure and blood sugar. It might also help you prevent weight-related diseases, such as heart disease, diabetes, arthritis and some cancers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eating too much or not being physically active enough will make you &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;. To maintain your weight, the calories you eat must equal the energy you burn. To lose weight, you must use more calories than you eat. A weight-control strategy might include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choosing low-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;fat&lt;/span&gt;, low-calorie foods&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eating smaller portions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drinking water instead of sugary drinks&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being physically active&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Weight Reduction Programs</content>
      <content name="mesh">Diet, Reducing</content>
      <content name="mesh">Weight Loss</content>
      <content name="groupName">Food and Nutrition</content>
      <content name="snippet"> If you are &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt;, you are not alone.  Sixty-six percent of adults in the U.S. are &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;overweight&lt;/span&gt; or obese.   Achieving a healthy weight can help you control  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="7" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/anesthesia.html">
      <content name="title">Anesthesia</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;If you are having surgery, your doctor will give you a drug called an anesthetic. Anesthetics reduce or prevent pain. There are four main types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Local: numbs one small area of the body. You stay awake and alert.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	Conscious or intravenous (IV) sedation: uses a mild sedative to relax you and pain medicine to relieve pain. You stay awake but may not remember the procedure afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Regional anesthesia: blocks pain in an area of the body, such an arm or leg. Epidural anesthesia, which is sometimes used during childbirth, is a type of regional anesthesia. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;	General anesthesia: affects your whole body. You go to sleep and feel nothing. You have no memory of the procedure afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The type of anesthesia your doctor chooses depends on many factors. These include the procedure you are having and your current health. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Anesthesia</content>
      <content name="groupName">Surgery and Rehabilitation</content>
      <content name="snippet"> If you are having surgery, your doctor will give you a drug called an anesthetic. Anesthetics reduce or prevent pain. There are four main types. 	Local:  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="8" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/breathingproblems.html">
      <content name="title">Breathing Problems</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Dyspnea</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Tachypnea</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Shortness of Breath</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;When you're short of breath, it's hard or uncomfortable for you to take in the oxygen your body needs. You may feel as if you're not getting enough air.  Sometimes mild breathing problems are from a stuffy nose or hard exercise. But shortness of breath can also be a sign of a serious disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many conditions can make you feel short of breath. Lung conditions such as asthma, emphysema or pneumonia cause breathing difficulties. So can problems with your trachea or bronchi, which are part of your airway system.  Heart disease can make you feel breathless if your heart cannot pump enough blood to supply oxygen to your body. Stress caused by anxiety can also make it hard for you to breathe. If you often have trouble breathing, it is important to find out the cause. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Dyspnea</content>
      <content name="mesh">Tachypnea</content>
      <content name="groupName">Lungs and Breathing</content>
      <content name="groupName">Symptoms</content>
      <content name="snippet"> When you're short of breath, it's hard or uncomfortable for you to take in the oxygen your body needs. You may feel as if you're not getting enough air.  Sometimes  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="9" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/schoolhealth.html">
      <content name="title">School Health</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Your child spends more time at school than anywhere else except home. Schools can have a major effect on children's health, by teaching about health and promoting healthy behaviors. The school building and environment should be a safe and healthy place for your child.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Schools work to prevent risky behaviors such as alcohol and tobacco use, inactivity or bullying.  They may also deal with specific health problems in students, such as asthma, &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;obesity&lt;/span&gt; and infectious diseases. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">School Health Services</content>
      <content name="groupName">Children and Teenagers</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... specific health problems in students, such as asthma, &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;obesity&lt;/span&gt; and infectious diseases. </content>
    </document>
  </list>
</nlmSearchResult>
